# Víctor Ponce López



#### Contact

vponcelop<at>gmail.com victorponce.info Bristol, United Kingdom

#### Languages

Catalan \*\*\*\*(native), Spanish ★★★★ (native), English \*\*\*\*

(advanced reading/writing, fluent oral).

Français \*\*\*\* (intermediate reading/writing, basics oral).

#### **Programming** Languages, Libs, Tools, **Web and Environments**

Python, MATLAB, C++/C#/C, R, PyCharm, Netbeans, Eclipse, VS/VC++, SVN/GIT, Redmine, LATEX, XML, PostgreSQL, SQL, MySQL, Hive, Spark, Hadoop, CodaLab, Kaggle, Bash, PHP/HTML/CSS/JavaScript;

**Deep Learning & Computer** 

**Vision** libraries and toolboxes: ♥ Tensorflow, PyTorch, Keras, GAN. CNN. LSTM. dlib. CUDA+CuDNN, Kinect™SDK, open{CV/NI/GL}, CNTK+; evolutionary computation and statistical pattern recognition: numpy, matplotlib, sklearn, optimtool, gatool, pmtk3, deap, pandas, statsmodel.

## **OS Preferences**

GNU/I inux ★★★★ Windows ★★★★ MacOS \*\*\*\* Android ★★★★ iOS \*\*\*\*

#### short bio

I am a Research Associate in the Dept. of Computer Science at the University of Bristol and member of the European Laboratory for Learning and Intelligent Systems (ELLIS). I was a Research Scientist in Eurecat at the Big Data Analytics Unit. I hold a PhD at the the Dept. of Mathematics and Computer Science, University of Barcelona (UB). I received my B.Sc. degree in Computer Science and Engineering at the Faculty of Mathematics of UB, and my M.Sc. degree in Artificial Intelligence at the Polytechnic University of Catalonia. I was affiliated to the Computer Vision Center -Autonomous University of Barcelona- and the Open University of Catalonia, in the groups HuPBA and SUNAI; and the group Qarma at the Laboratoire d'Informatique Fondamentalle, Aix-Marseille Université.

## **experience**

2017-Present **ELLIS Society & University of Bristol**  Bristol, United Kingdom

Member of the European Laboratory for Learning and Intelligent Systems (ELLIS). Postdoctoral Research Associate, Dept. of Computer Science.

- Time-Series Predictive Analysis of Seasonal Ground Surface Deformation.
- Computer Vision for Human Activity Recognition in Home Healthcare.
- · Domain Adaptation, Self-Supervised Learning, GANs, Person Re-IDentification.

2010-2017 Eurecat Technology Center of Catalonia, University of Barcelona, Open University of Catalonia, Computer Vision Center, and Dept. of Justice, Government of Catalonia

> Research Scientist, PostDoc, Collaboration in Research projects, international PhD stay, 40+ scientific publications and peer-reviews, teaching and material preparation, organization/attendance on international conferences, events, and seminars.

- 4 impact factor journals, 17 conference proceedings, and 1 book chapter.
- · ChaLearn Looking At People collaboration with Microsoft, NVIDIA, Google, Amazon, Disney, Facebook, Orange, MWC-GSMA.
- Research projects on human behavior analysis within real-world domains.

Past-2010 Barcelona's Council: Dept. of Education, Culture and Welfare

Barcelona, Spain

Software Engineer, IT Services.

## education

2012-2016 Ph.D. in Mathematics and Computer Science

Faculty of Mathematics, University of Barcelona

Dissertation: "Evolutionary Bags of Space-Time Features for Human Analysis." Cum

Laude (spanish) and International Mention.

2010-2012 M.Sc in Artificial Intelligence

Polytechnic University of Catalonia, University of Barcelona, and Rovira i Virgili University.

Dissertation: "Multi-Modal Human Gesture Recognition combining Dynamic Program-

ming and Probabilistic Methods." With Honors.

2006-2010 **B.Sc in Computer Science: Systems engineering** 

Faculty of Mathematics, University of Barcelona.

Dissertation: "Analysis of Oral and Gestural Expression using an Artificial Vision Sys-

tem." With Honors.

#### extracurricular

**Driving license** 2006-Present

**Martial Arts licenses** Hapkido 2<sup>nd</sup> Black Belt 2004-Present

1998-2004 **Musical language and Piano licenses** 

#### interests

I'm a research & technology passionate. My main interests are computer vision, machine learning, and evolutionary computation for real-world applications. I like to be up to date with latest research and cutting-edge technology to foresee next future trends and needs.